《疯狂的麦克斯3》
呀呼
Yahoo!
- 正中红心 - 没错 老爸
- Bull's-eye! - You bet, Dad!
你回家去吧
You go straight home.
好的
Okay!
下去喽
Bombs away!
再会了 烂人
Sayonara, sucker!
(巴特镇替大家打造美好明天)
没有防腐剂 纯水
No preservatives, just pure water!
清凉干净的水
Cool, clear water.
喂 过来啊 咱们做点交易吧
Hey, step up, schmuck, get some dealing done.
我卖的是水
Hay, that's my go.
你难道不懂吗？这是水 在这里没水活不成
Hey, don't you understand? This is water. You can't live without it.
辐射尘真要人命 是吧 祝你有个美好一天 来买水唷
What's a little fallout, huh? Have a nice day! Water!
你去拿一袋谷物来
You get a sack of grain...
或提供两小时服务的女人
...or a woman for two hours.
- 你想交易什么？- 我要找一个人
- What are you trading? - I'm looking for someone.
你到底要不要交易？
Are you trading or not?
他驾驶一车队骆驼
He was driving a team of camels.
这里是交易之地 赚点利润 做点生意
People come here to trade, make a little profit, do a little business.
你若没东西交易 就没资格来到巴特镇
If you've nothing to trade, you've got no business in Bartertown.
我只要进去一小时就好
An hour on the inside, that's all.
- 下一个 - 我拿一身本领交易
- Next! - I got skills, I can trade them.
抱歉 妓院人手已满
Sorry. The brothel's full.
一小时就好
One hour.
- 你若找到他 然后呢？- 我会要求他物归原主
- And if you find him, what then? - I'll ask him to return what's mine.
喔 到时他一定会很想赎罪
Oh, and of course he'll be desperate to clear his conscience.
是的
He will be.
- 你真那么厉害？- 嗯
- Are you that good? - Mm-hm.
或许你的确有交易的本领
Perhaps you've got something to trade after all.
你就开口吧
Keep talking.
拿你二十四小时阳寿
Twenty-four hours of your life.
换你将取回被偷走的东西
In return, you'll get back what was stolen.
这交易不错
Sounds like a bargain.
这不是交易咱们谈谈 进来吧
It's not. Let's talk. Come inside.
把武器放在这里 这是法律规定
Leave your weapons here. It's the law.
- 记住啦 就是这种交通工具… - 等一下
- Remember, this is the vehicle... - Wait a minute.
- 让底特律破产 - 喂
- ...that sent Detroit broke. - Hey. Hey!
你从哪里拿到这些骆驼？
Where did you get these animals?
最棒的单峰骆驼 沙漠之舟
The glorious dromedary. The ship of the desert.
具有独立悬吊系统 动力方向操纵 没有排放控制器
They've got independent suspension, power steering and no emission control.
现在就把它们骑走
Ride them away now.
开价吧
Make me an offer.
(原子咖啡店)
大姨娘 来了一位战士
A warrior, Aunty.
他失去一切 寻觅一份交易
Lost everything. Looking for a deal.
但他只是个邋遢不起眼的人
But he's just a raggedy man.
他动作灵敏
He's quick.
铁人…
Ironbar...
你觉得他行吗？
...think he can do it?
或许吧
Maybe.
你从前做过什么？
And what did you do before this?
我当过警察 司机
I was a cop, a driver.
真是风水轮流转啊
But how the world turns.
曾经风光一世 如今沦为阶下囚
One day cock of the walk, next, a feather duster.
汤汤 弹奏悲伤曲调吧
Play something, Ton Ton. Something tragic.
你可知道我从前是谁？
Do you know who I was?
无名小卒
Nobody.
但在大限过后 我仍活命
Except on the day after, I was still alive.
无名小卒便有机会闯出一份名堂
This nobody had a chance to be somebody.
讲了这么多关于我的事 要喝点水吗？吃水果？
So much for history. Anyway... Water? Fruit?
恭喜 你是第一位通过甄试的人
Congratulations. You're the first to survive the audition.
喝吧
Drink.
没事的
It's okay.
跟我来
Come with me.
你看看 先生 这些都是我造的
Look around, mister. All this I built.
费尽千辛万苦打造而成
Up to my armpits in blood and shit.
曾经是一片沙漠 如今是一座城镇
Where there was desert, now there's a town.
曾经盗贼肆虐 如今银货两讫
Where there was robbery, there's trade.
曾经哀鸿遍野 如今一片生机
Where there was despair, now there's hope.
文明
Civilization.
我愿意不计任何代价保护它
I'll do anything to protect it.
今天的代价是杀一个人 你说呢？
Today it's necessary to kill a man. What do you say?
你愿意付出什么代价？
What do you pay?
我重新给你装备 交通工具 牲畜 还有燃料
I'll re-equip you. Vehicles, animals. Fuel, if you want.
非常优厚的提议
It's a generous offer.
为什么找上我？你有战士 有武器 你只要下令就好
Why me? You've got warriors, you've got weapons. Just give the order.
我们面对的情况非比寻常
We are dealing with subtleties here.
他们不是敌人 几乎像是家人
This is no enemy. It's almost family.
是啊 真"文明"
Oh, I see, real civilized.
你不必管理由 只要负责行事
The reasons don't concern you, just the conditions.
你到底同不同意协定？
You want the deal or not?
唔
Huh.
第一 你绝对不能让任何人知道 你替大姨娘工作
The first is that no one knows you're working for Aunty.
你出手击败他 然后离开
You hit him, you go.
第二 要公平打斗
The second is, it's a fair fight.
第三 必须致对方于死地
And third is, it's to the death.
对方是谁？
Who's the bunny?
那地方叫地下世界 即巴特镇取得能源之地
Called it Underworld. It's where Bartertown gets its energy.
怎么 石油或天然气？
What, oil, natural gas?
猪
Pigs.
- 像那种猪？- 没错
- You mean pigs like those? - That's right.
- 狗屎 - 是猪屎
- Bullshit. - Pigshit.
- 什么？- 猪屎
- What? - Pigshit.
电灯 马达 交通工具…
The lights, the motors, the vehicles...
全靠一种叫沼气的高能量瓦斯运作
...all run by a high-powered gas called methane.
而沼气来自猪屎
Methane comes from pigshit.
你自己看 你看到什么？
Have a look. Tell me what you see.
我看到一只大猪扛着一只小猪
I see a big guy giving a little guy a piggyback.
老大爆炸王 他们是共同体
MasterBlaster. They're a unit.
他们甚至有共同的名字
They even share the same name.
小的那只叫老大 他出脑力
The little one is called Master. He's the brains.
他掌管地下世界
He runs Underworld.
另一个是爆炸王 他出劳力
The other one is Blaster. He's the muscle.
他们的组合阵容十分强大
Together they can be very powerful.
他们也很自大
And they are also arrogant.
我们想要保住大脑 废掉身体
We want to keep the brain, dump the body.
他很壮 他有多强？
He's big. How good is he?
他哼一口气便能让人致命
He can beat most men with his breath.
我要仔细瞧瞧他 我该怎么渗入？
I want a closer look at him. How do I get in there?
- 那是所工厂 去找份工作吧 - 我对沼气一无所知
- It's a factory, isn't it? Ask for work. - I know nothing about methane.
你会产屎吧？
You can shovel shit, can't you?
喂 你
Hey, you!
咱们来谈谈
Let's talk!
嘿
Hey!
来 自由人 来帮帮罪犯吧 你不想沦落到和我同样下场吧
Come on, free man, come help a convict. You don't want to end up like me, do you?
你被判关多久？
How long are you in for?
终身监
The big one. Life. Ha, ha.
因为杀了一只猪？
For killing a pig?
我得喂活我的孩子
I had to feed the kids.
别替我担心 在这里终生监只有两三年
Ah, doesn't worry me. Down here life's two, three years.
那个修理工黑手指在哪里？
Where is that bum mechanic Blackfinger?
嗨
Heh. Hi.
我们有麻烦了
Uh, we got a real problem.
两磅炸弹 己准备好开炸
Twelve pounds of dynamite, all set to blow.
麻烦？你是专家 解除武装
Problem? You expert! Disarm!
好的
Right.
嗯 嘿
Uh, heh.
这是很高阶的工作 一个不小心 整个 地方就会被炸为平地
It's a class job. One mistake, it'll blow the crap out of this place.
- 是真的 - 快想办法
- Literally. - Think what to do!
好的
Yeah. Right. Heh.
炸弹被接到一个计时器
Uh, now, the dynamite is connected to the timing device...
然后被接到一个开关 我找不到这开关
...which is connected to the switch, which I can't find...
那开关则接到…
...which is connected to the, uh...
电池
...battery.
- 我就来切断电池 - 我可不会那么做
- I'll disconnect the battery! - I wouldn't do that if I were you.
你是谁？
Who you?
- 我是麦克斯 - 你够聪明
- Me Max. - You smart.
- 聪明让我行遍天下 - 解除武装
- That's my vehicle. - Disarm!
- 多少钱？- 不交易 只做事
- How much? - No trade. Do!
抓住他
Fetch!
由我发号施令 我是老大
Me order. Me Master!
由我掌管巴特镇
Me run Bartertown!
是啊 所以你们才会在屎堆打滚
Sure, that's why you live in shit.
不是屎 是能源
Not shit! Energy!
随便你怎么叫 闻起来还是屎臭冲天
Ugh. Call it what you like, still smells like shit to me.
不是屎 是能源 没有能源就没有城镇
Not shit! Energy! No energy, no town!
我是阿拉伯国王
Me king Arab!
是啊 我是小精灵仙子
Sure. Me, fairy princess.
禁止输出能源
Embargo, on!
禁止输出能源 关闭主阀门
Embargo on! Main valve off!
四 三 二…
Four, three, two...
拜托 现在又怎么了？
For God's sake, what now?
巴特镇由谁掌管？
Who run Bartertown?
该死 我告诉过你 别再次禁止输出能源
Damn it. I told you, no more embargoes.
再关更多 爆炸王
More, Blaster.
巴特镇由谁掌管？
Who run Bartertown?
你知道是谁
You know who.
你说啊
Say.
老大爆炸王
MasterBlaster.
说大声点
Say loud.
老大爆炸王
MasterBlaster.
老大爆炸王怎样？
MasterBlaster what?
老大爆炸王掌管巴特镇
MasterBlaster runs Bartertown.
再大声点
Louder!
老大爆炸王掌管巴特镇
MasterBlaster runs Bartertown.
解除禁止输出能源
Lift embargo.
好的 重新排队 快点
All right, back in line. Come on!
- 你要脚放在脸上？- 不
- You want foot in face? - Uh-uh.
解除武装
Disarm.
真乖
Good boy.
在这里 爆炸王
Over here, Blaster.
- 先生 你为啥事进来？- 没事
- Hey, mister. What are you laying for? - Nothing.
- 你是谁？- 谁都不是
- Who are you? - Nobody.
不 先生 我能感受到 色子开始滚动了
No, mister, I can feel it. The dice are rolling!
我要骆驼 交通工具 食物 水 沼气
I want my camels, my vehicle, food, water, methane.
哈？
Huh?
- 没问题 - 你说是公平过招
- Deal. - Okay, you said a fair fight.
- 什么意思？- 依据法律规定进行
- What do you mean by that? - As provided by the law.
闪电擂台
Thunderdome.
两人赤手空拳过招 没有评审 不能重来 无法逃命
Two men, hand-to-hand. No jury, no appeal, no parole.
两人进 一人出
Two men enter, one man leaves.
武器呢？
Weapons?
任何事情都可能发生 由机会决定
Anything's possible. Chance decides.
闪电擂台 我该如何上擂台？
Thunderdome. How do I get in there?
很简单 找个人单挑
That's easy. Pick a fight.
祝大家玩得开心
Everybody have a good time!
那是我的交通工具 我要拿回它
That's my vehicle and I want it back!
我听不清楚 听起来像有人下命令
Hearing wonky. Sounds like an order.
- 没错 - 这可不得了了
- That's right. - Yumping Yesus!
他居然这么说 头壳坏掉了
Him sad. Brain broken.
让我来解释
Me explain.
这是我的交通工具 你…
This my vehicle. You...
是行人 继续前进
...pedestrian! Drive on!
给你三秒钟 否则扭断你脖子
Three seconds, break neck. One.
二…
Two.
老大爆炸王
MasterBIaster!
遵从法律
Listen to the law!
大姨娘 有两人发生争执
Aunty, two men in dispute.
这些是我们的目击证人 大姨娘
These our witness, Aunty.
我们被欺负了 要讨回公道
Us suffer bad. Us want justice.
我们要闪电擂台
We want Thunderdome!
你们知道法律规定 是两人进 一人出
You know the law. Two men enter, one man leaves.
两人进 一人出
Two men enter, one man leaves.
爆炸王出场 二十人进 只有他出
This Blaster. Twenty men enter, only him leave.
那就是你的决定了 闪电擂台
Then it's your choice. Thunderdome.
(闪电擂台 现场过招)
大姨娘 大姨娘 大姨娘
Aunty! Aunty! Aunty!
欢迎光临闪电擂台比赛现场
Welcome to another edition of Thunderdome!
大家听好
Listen on! Listen on!
我说的是事实
This is the truth of it.
争执将引发杀戮 杀戮将引发战争
Fighting leads to killing, and killing gets to warring.
那将让我们濒临死亡
And that was damn near the death of us all.
瞧瞧我们现在 一片毁灭 每个人日子过得苦不堪言
Look at us now, busted up and everyone talking about hard rain.
但我们很清楚 巴特镇已学到许多教训
But we've learned by the dust of them all. Bartertown's learned.
现在 当有人对质斗争 就在此地开始
Now when men get to fighting, it happens here.
也在此地结束
And it finishes here.
两人进 一人出
Two men enter, one man leaves.
现在 我有两个人
And right now, I've got two men.
两个充满恐惧的人
Two men with a gut full of fear.
各位先生女士 男孩和女孩
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls...
死亡时间已来到
...dying time's here!
他是毁灭王 杀人机器
He's the ball cracker. Death on foot.
你们熟知他 你们爱他 他是爆炸王
You know him. You love him! He's Blaster!
挑战者来自荒野国度
The challenger, direct from out of the Wasteland.
他够狠 够帅 够疯狂 他是…
He's bad. He's beautiful. He's crazy! it's...
他是一个无名氏
It's the man with no name!
闪电擂台很简单 选择武器 任意使用
Thunderdome's simple. Get to the weapons, use them anyway you can.
我知道你们不会达反规定 因为没有任何规定
I know you won't break the rules. There aren't any.
记得你们所在之处
Remember where you are.
这里是闪电擂台
This is Thunderdome.
死亡正在聆听 它将带走第一个尖叫的人
Death is listening, and will take the first man that screams.
准备
Prepare!
两人进 一人出
Two men enter, one man leaves!
哇
Whoa!
加油
Come on!
爆炸王 爆炸王 爆炸王
Blaster, Blaster, Blaster.
哈？
Huh?
杀了他 杀了他 杀了他
Kill him, kill him, kill him.
- 杀了他 - 杀了他 杀了他
- Kill him! - Kill him! Kill him!
- 你很清楚法律规定 - 这里是闪电擂台
- You know the law! - This is Thunderdome!
杀了他
Kill him!
不 瞧瞧他的脸
No, no! Look at his face!
他有一颗童稚的心
He's got the mind of a child.
不是他的错
It's not his fault.
爆炸王 对不起
Blaster, I'm sorry.
这没包括在我们的协定里
This wasn't part of the deal.
协定？
Deal?
"协定" 什么意思？
What do you mean, "deal"?
你一定感受到了 你刚才掌握了一切
You must have tasted it. It was in your hands.
- 你原本可以赢的 - 我在跟你说话
- You had it all! - I'm talking to you!
你说什么 "协定"？
What do you mean, "deal"?
不再给你们沼气了
No more methane!
这地方就完蛋了
This place, finished!
不 小矮子
No, little man.
好戏才刚开始呢
We've only just begun.
喔 不
Oh, no.
糟糕
No, no.
不
No!
不 不
No, no.
打开
Open it.
两人进 一人出
Two men enter. One man leaves!
这算什么？
What's this?
算什么？
你们以为我不懂法律？当初不是我写的吗？
Do you think I don't know the law? Wasn't it me who wrote it?
我说这个人违反了法律
And I say that this man has broken the law.
不管是对是错 我们已谈好协定
Right or wrong, we had a deal.
法律规定:"破坏协定 面对大法轮"
And the law says, "Bust a deal, face the wheel."
破坏协定 面对大法轮
Bust a deal and face the wheel.
破坏协定面对大法轮
Bust a deal, face the wheel.
我们的性命千钧一发
All our lives hang by a thread.
现在有个人等候被判刑
Now we've got a man waiting for sentence.
但是当你想和法律过招时…
But ain't it the truth? You take your chances with the law.
正义就像掷骰子
Justice is only a roll of the dice...
丢铜板或是转大法轮
...a flip of the coin, a turn of the wheel.
(死亡 地下世界 大姨娘的选择)
(集中营 无罪开释 做苦工)
(地下世界 截肢)
集中营 集中营 集中营
Gulag. Gulag. Gulag.
快把它修好
Fix it.
巴特镇由你掌管
You run Bartertown.
你自己修理
You fix.
不
No!
不要猪 不要
Not pigs! No!
够了
That's enough!
你们想利用他还是杀了他？把他弄上来
Do you want to use him or kill him? Bring him up.
老大 照铁人的话做
Master, do what lronbar says.
是 我会的
Uh, uh... I Will. Yeah, I Will.
莎凡娜
Savannah!
芬恩 你看
Finn, look.
是他 我找到他了
It's him. I finded him.
是沃克机长
It's Captain Walker.
- 他说什么？- 他还没说话
- What's his talk? - He ain't made no wordstuff.
长途跋涉 或许他累坏了
It's a long track. Maybe he's burned out.
或许他正在听
Maybe. Maybe he's just listening.
沃克？哈罗？沃克？
Walker? Hello? Walker?
或许他正在说话 只是我们听不到
Maybe he's talking, but we ain't hearing.
你看他的嘴唇没动
You see his lips ain't moving.
不是用说话 是用音波
Not with wordstuff, with sonic.
那根本不可能 音波根本就是胡说八道
That ain't never gonna work, sonic-bonic bullshit!
就在这里 三角州狐狸X光
This here's Delta-Fox-X-Ray.
你能听到我吗？
Can you hear me?
三角州狐狸X光
Delta-Fox-X-Ray.
请回应
Come in.
有人在吗？
Is anybody out there?
你能听到我吗 沃克？
Can you read me, Walker?
三角州狐狸X光
Delta-Fox-X-Ray.
请回应
Come in.
有人在吗？
Is anybody out there?
你能听到我吗 沃克？
Can you hear me, Walker?
怎样啊 医生？
Eh, what's up, doc?
嘿 带我和你一起去
Hey, take me with you!
你能听到我吗 沃克？
Can you hear me, Walker?
- 飞啊 沃克 - 飞啊 沃克 飞吧
- Fly, Walker! - Fly, Walker, fly!
飞啊 沃克 飞吧
Fly, Walker, fly!
你们是谁？
Who are you?
你们是谁？你们是谁？
Who are you? Who are you?
安静
Quiet!
安静 安静 安静
Quiet! Quiet! Quiet!
闭嘴
Shut up!
闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
够了
Enough!
够了 够了 够了
Enough! Enough! Enough!
你们是谁？
Who are you?
你们是谁？你们是谁？
Who are you? Who are you?
我们是等候的人
We's the waiting ones.
等候什么？
Waiting for what?
等候你
Waiting for you.
等你… 等你…
For you. For you.
你们认为我是谁？
Who do you think I am?
我想他在测试我们
I think he be testing us.
这是场测试 沃克 你以为我们都在偷懒？
This a testing, Walker? You reckon we been slack?
我不知道 或许你们这阵子都很偷懒
Well, I don't know. Maybe you've been slack.
我们才没有 我们把它照顾得很好 都在这里
We ain't. We kept it straight. It's all there.
一切都做了记号 一切都记住了 你自己看
Everything marked, everything 'membered. You wait, you'll see.
大家都知道 我是首位长征者
This you knows. I be First Tracker.
现在应该由我阐述故事
And times past count I done the Tell.
但并不是我找到沃克 而是莎凡娜
But it weren't me that tumbled Walker. It was Savannah.
所以应该由她负责述说这个故事
So it's only right that she take the Tell.
这不是一个人故事 这是我们大家的故事
This ain't one body's story. It's the story of us all.
我们口述传承历史 你们必须仔细听并牢记
We got it mouth-to-mouth. You got to listen it and 'member.
因为你们今天听到的故事 明天将要转述给下一代
Because what you hears today you got to tell the birthed tomorrow.
我现在看的 是我们的过去
I'm looking behind us now...
在很久很久以前
...across the count of time...
就在古老历史渊远深处
...down the long haul, into history back.
我看到末日的开端
I sees the end what were the start.
那是大毁灭 充满痛苦折磨
It's Pox-Eclipse, full of pain!
在那场毁灭中诞生了漫天尘灰 以及恐惧时代
And out of it were birthed crackling dust and fearsome time.
那是寒冷的冬天
It were full-on winter...
死神对每个人都不放过
...and Mr. Dead chasing them all.
但死神唯一逮不到的就是沃克机长
But one he couldn't catch. That were Captain Walker.
他召集一群人 然后飞向天空
He gathers up a gang, takes to the air and flies the sky!
他们远离家园 向高褛大厦告别 说拜拜
So they left their homes, said bidey-bye to the high-scrapers...
拜拜
Bidey-bye.
他们把所有知识留在脑后
...and what were left of the knowing, they left behind.
有人说风被搅拌了
Some say the wind just stoppered.
有人说那是所谓的乱流
Others reckon it were a gang called Turbulence.
在坠机之后…
And after the wreck...
有人被死神带走了
...some had been jumped by Mr. Dead...
但有些人比较幸运 辗转漂流到这里
...but some had got the luck, and it leads them here.
他们看了这里 感觉这里就像他们所谓的"地球"
One look and they's got the hots for it. They word it "Planet Earth."
他们说 "我们不需要知识 我们可以住在这里"
And they says, "We don't need the knowing. We can live here."
"我们不需要知识 我们可以住在这里"
"We don't need the knowing. We can live here."
随时光不断流逝
Time counts and keeps counting.
他们开始怀念他们的过去
They gets missing what they had.
他们很寂寞 非常怀念高楼大厦以及录影带
They get so lonely for the high-scrapers and the video.
录影带
Videos!
他们拍照片 以便记住曾经孰知的一切
And they do pictures so they'd 'member all the knowing they lost.
记得这个吗？
'Member this?
明日世界
Tomorrow-morrow Land!
记的这个吗？
'Member this?
光之河
The River of Light!
记得这个吗？
'Member this?
天空之船
Skyraft!
记得这个吗？
'Member this?
沃克机长
Captain Walker!
- 记得这个吗？- 沃克夫人
- 'Member this? - Mrs. Walker!
沃克机长从长途班机中 挑选几个年轻人
Then Captain Walker picked them of an age and good for a long haul.
一共二十人 这些人大逃亡
They counted twenty, and that were them. The great leaving.
"救援队伍一破晓便出发"
"Rescue party departed at first light...
"由班机机长沃克带领"
...led by Flight Captain G.L. Walker."
"求神垂怜我们的灵魂"
"May God have mercy on our souls."
他们 跟下一代道别说拜拜
They said bidey-bye to them what they'd birthed.
突然间 他们回头望
And from out of the nothing they looked back...
沃克机长大喊:"等等 我们其中一个会来"
...and Captain Walker hollered, "Wait, one of us will come."
"等等 我们其中一个会来"
"Wait, one of us will come."
某个人果真来了
And somebody did come.
沃克
Walker.
我们衷心感谢你 沃克机长
We's heartful to you, Captain Walker.
我们已准备好了 带我们回家吧
We's ready now. Take us home.
我们保持得很好 全部完好
We kept it straight! It's all there, ain't it?
每件束西都做了记号 每件事都铭记在心
Everything marked, everything 'membered!
是的 你们保存得非常好 你们一点都没有偷懒
Yeah, you kept it real good. You ain't been slack at all.
- 我们还等什么？- 不是我
- Why are we waiting for? - That ain't me.
- 你们找错人了 - 别开玩笑了 机长
- You got the wrong guy. - Quit joshing, captain.
- 是啊 快乘风飞行 - 我们要看明日世界
- Yeah, catch the wind. - We got to see Tomorrow-morrow Land!
回家 去明日世界
Home! Tomorrow-morrow Land!
听他说
Listen him!
是有些地方像这样 城市
There were places like these. Uh, cities.
- 那种地方叫城市 有许多城市 - 城市 城市
- They were called cities. Lots of them. - Cities. Cities!
他们知道许多事情 他们有高楼大厦
They had lots of knowing of a lot of things. They had skyscrapers...
- 高楼大厦？- 录影带 还有音波…
- Skyscrapers? - ...videos and they had the sonic...
但后来发生这件事
But, uh, then this happened.
发生这场… 大毁灭 一切都结束了 再也没有城市
This, uh... This Pox-Eclipse happened, and it's finished. It isn't there anymore.
你们必须了解 这里就是你们的家园
You got to understand that, uh, this is home...
没有明日世界
...and there's no Tomorrow Land...
而且我不是沃克机长
...and I ain't Captain Walker.
就是现在
This is it!
我们已经准备好出发了 机长
We's loaded and waiting, captain.
现在风特别强 机长 我们出发吧
We got the wind up our arse, captain. Let's go!
谁要一起走？我们要离开了
Who's coming? We's pulling on a leaving.
你们哪都走不了 别白费力气时间了
There ain't gonna be no leavings. All that stuff's just jerking time.
我们的做法不一样
We's working it different.
你们难道没看到吗？他根本无法赶上那道风
Ain't you seen nothing? He couldn't catch the wind.
才没有所谓的天空之船 没有救援行动
There weren't no skyrafting. There ain't gonna be no salvage.
这里便是明日世界 他已经证明给我们看了
This is our Tomorrow-morrow Land. He's proof of that.
你们全都被洗脑了 他若不是沃克机长 又是谁呢？
Program! All of you program. If he ain't Captain Walker, who is he?
他和我们没有两样 他是徒步来到这里
He ain't no different to us, that's who. He slogged it out on foot.
如果他能到这里 我们便能回得去
If he can get here, we can get back.
他的个子并没有比我们大
He ain't much bigger than us.
副驾驶都办到了 我们为何不能？
Copilot did it. So why can't we?
这才像话 谁要跟我们走？
That's the trick of it. Who's coming?
- 不… - 横越一片空无？你们难道不记得？
- No... - Across the nothing? Don't you 'member?
你们当初找到他时 他只剩下半条命
When you finded him, he were half jumped by Mr. Dead.
没有人说外面的情况好应付 我们很清楚
Nobody's saying it ain't a hard slog. We knows that now.
但我们若要获得知识做法 就没有简单的办法
If we wants the knowing the doing, there ain't no easy ride.
没有所谓的知识和做法
There ain't no knowing and ain't no doing!
没有天空之船也没有音波 你们出去闯只是一片空
There ain't no skyraft and there ain't no sonic. You slog out there to nothing!
比空无还可怕
Worse than nothing.
你们首先会遏到 一个龌龊的地方 叫巴特镇
The first place you'll find is a sleaze pit called Bartertown.
如果你们没被大地吞噬 保证会被那地方生吞活剥
If the earth doesn't swallow you up, that place sure as hell will.
你听到他说的 没有所谓的明日世界
Listen him! There ain't no Tomorrow-morrow Land!
我们已经听过他说的话 全是一派胡言
We done that! He's got wordstuff from his ass to his mouth.
身上有果汁的人 跟我们走
Whoever's got the juice, track with us.
谢谢
Thanks.
现在 给我听好
Now listen good!
我不是沃克机长 我是个不畏惧死神的人
I'm not Captain Walker. I'm the guy who keeps Mr. Dead in his pocket.
我说我们应该 留在这里
And I say we're gonna stay here.
我们将会活到长命百岁 我们将心存感激
And we're gonna live a long time and we're gonna be thankful.
好吗？
Right?
继续走
Keep tracking.
史雷克
Slake!
- 去把其他人带回来 - 来吧
- Get the others. - Come.
他们走了 你得去把他们找回来
They've gone. You got to get them back!
快点 他们走了 史古鲁斯放他们走了
Come on! They've gone! Scrooloose let them go.
莎凡娜带走他们 他们走进沙漠了
Savannah's taken them. They're in the nothing.
快点 你必须帮我 你必须帮我把他们带回来
Come on, you got to help me! Come, you got to help me get them back!
莎凡娜和盖可 他根本没办法走路
Savannah and Gekko. He can hardly walk.
小芬恩 天鱼先生和库莎 她随时就要生孩子了 还有副驾驶…
Little Finn, Mr. Skyfish, and Cusha. She's gonna pop any day now. And Copilot...
快点
Come on!
- 走了多远？- 半个夜晚
- How long? - Half a night.
或许更短 他们已深入沙漠了
Maybe less. They be deep in the nothing.
- 他们没带太多水 - 无所谓
- Ain't got much water. - Makes no difference.
他们会被沙子吞噬
They'll be swallowed by the sand.
你必须把他们带回来 机长
You gotta get them back, captain!
别一直叫我机长 别一直发出那种声音 别鬼叫了
Stop with the "Captain." Stop. Stop the noise, will you? Stop the noise!
我需要愈多水愈好
I need as much water as I can carry.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我要替我的朋友们展开救援行动
I's coming salvage for my buddies.
我们需要一个猎人
We needs a hunter.
他自己可以 好吗？
He holds his own, okay?
救命啊 救救我
Help! Help me!
什么事？
Huh? What?
快点 咱们走
Quick, let's trek!
那是明日世界？
Is it Tomorrow-morrow Land?
不 是巴特镇
No. Bartertown.
那是我们唯一的机会
It's our only chance.
进去 我们随后就进去
Get in, we're right behind you.
等一下 大家跟紧一点
Wait! Stick together!
这里是哪里？
Where are we?
- 我什么都看不到 - 这里是巴特镇
- I can't see nothing. - It's Bartertown.
好臭
It stinks!
吐巴 厍莎 等等我
Tubba, Cusha, wait up! Wait up!
走哪边？
Which way?
往光亮处走
Head for the light.
- 其他人呢？- 他们在前面
- Where are the others? - They've gone ahead.
- 多远？- 非常远
- How far? - A long way.
- 你看得到他们吗？- 一点点
- Can you see them? - Only just!
我们在做什么？我们有什么计划？
What are we doing? What's our program?
我们要找一个人
We're looking for someone.
在这里？你在开玩笑吧？
In here? This is jerking time!
有一个矮子 他知道很多事情 明白吗？
A little guy, got the knowing of a lot of things. Understand?
- 明白 - 明白就闭嘴
- Yeah. - Yeah, well, shut up!
会看到什么 机长？
What's to see, captain?
安静
Shh! Quiet!
是他 机长 那个小矮子
It's him, captain! It's the little guy!
矮？我看他是全世界最小的人 搞什么？机长 他有啥用？
Little? He's the smallest! What the fuck, captain. What use is he?
安静
Shh! Quiet!
- 其他人呢？- 在外面
- Where are the others? - Out there.
史古伊 咱们飞吧
Screwy, let's fly!
对不起
Excuse me.
嘘
Shh.
Shh!
等一下
Hold it!
记住 无论你去哪里 你总是在的
Remember, no matter where you go, there you are.
嗨
Hi.
大家上车吧
All aboard!
快走
Go!
抓稳啰
Hang on!
先追人 晚点再付钱
Chase now, pay later.
巴特镇 听我说
Bartertown! Listen to me!
注意听
Listen!
- 巴特镇 - 注意听
- Bartertown! - Listen!
你们打算跑去哪里？
Where are you gonna run?
你们打算躲在哪里？听我说
Where are you gonna hide? Listen to me!
巴特镇将存活下去
Bartertown will live!
把小矮子找出来
Find the little man.
把他活捉回来给我
Bring him back to me alive!
我们将重新改造
We Will rebuild!
绝不宽恕把他带走的人
For those who took him, no mercy.
现在有什么计划？
So, what's the plan?
计划？
Plan?
没有计划
There ain't no plan.
天鱼 你看
Skyfish, look!
这一定就是了
It's got to be!
这是音波
The sonic.
盖可找到了
Gekko got it straight.
这里是三角州狐狸X光
This is Delta-Fox-X-Ray.
- 三角州狐狸X光 - 请回应
- Delta-Fox-X-Ray. - Come in.
你能听到我吗？完毕
Do you read me? Over.
请回应 你能听到我吗？三角州狐狸X光
Come in. Do you read me? Delta-Fox-X-Ray.
请回应 完毕 你能听到我吗？
Come on, over. Do you read me?
欢迎收听 请打开书本看第一页
Welcome. Open your book at page one.
现在请跟我念
Now repeat after me.
早
Good morning.
- 早安 - 早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
- 你要去哪里？- 你要去哪里？
- Where are you going? - Where are you going?
我要回家
I am going home.
- 我要回家 - 我要回家
- I am going home. - I am going home.
我要回家
I am going home.
哈
Aah!
他把那个人抓走了
He's got the man!
杀猪的
Ah, Pigkiller!
等一下
Wait...
黑手指 拔掉栓钉
Blackfinger! Pull the pin!
快点
Do it now!
等一下 黑手指 抓住
Hold it, Blackfinger! Hold it! Hold it!
啊
Aah!
把他还来
Give him back!
放手 放手
Let go! Let go!
黑手指 放手
Blackfinger, let go!
我抱住你了 我们要回家了
I've got you now. We're going home!
你没事了
You'll be all right.
快点
Come on now!
呃
Ugh.
我们要数到三
We're gonna count to three.
一…
One.
二呢？
What happened to two?
这是抢劫
This is a stickup!
任何人敢动的话就完蛋了
Anybody moves, and they're dead meat!
我想我们都完蛋了
Oh, I think we're all dead meat!
爸 我们完蛋了 我们完蛋了
Dad! Dad! We're dead meat! We're dead meat!
- 爸 我们完蛋了 - 好的 儿子
- Dad! We're dead meat! - Okay, son.
- 快点上飞机 - 好了 别闹了
- Quick, get in the plane! - Okay, now.
他跑去哪了？
Which way did he go?
- 我警告过你了 老爸 - 快跟我来
- I warned you, Dad! - Follow me!
- 你 - 我
- You! - Me?
今天是你走运的日子
You. It's your lucky day.
- 是吗？- 嗯
- It is? - Uh-huh.
你有一架飞机
You got a plane.
是吗？
I have?
它或许能救你一命
It might just save your life.
- 是吗？- 嗯
- It Will? - Uh-huh.
好的 起飞吧
All right, let her go!
快点啊
Come on, come on.
有什么问题？
What's the problem?
我们无法起飞
We're not gonna get off the ground.
飞机超重
We're overloaded!
爸 快想办法
Dad, you better do something!
- 还等什么 快点发动 - 没办法
- Kick her in the guts. - Not gonna make it.
跑道不够长
There's not enough runway.
我们别无选择
We haven't got any choice.
在他们…
Between them...
和我们之间 跑道不够长
...and us, there's not enough runway.
会够的
There will be.
啊
Agh!
这个嘛…
Well.
我们俩可真是旗鼓相当
Ain't we a pair...
邋遢男
...raggedy man.
再会 战士
Goodbye, soldier.
大家都知晓 岁月如梭
This you knows. The years travel fast.
我一再重复述说故事
And time after time, I've done the Tell.
这不是一个人的故事 这是我们大家的故事
But this ain't one body's Tell. It's the Tell of us all.
你们听了以后必须记得
And you got to listen it and 'member.
因为你们今天听到的故事 明天将转述给下一代
'Cause what you hears today, you got to tell the newborn tomorrow.
我现在看的是我们的过去历史
I's looking behind us now, into history back.
我看到那些幸运儿有机会 远渡重洋返回家园
I sees those of us that got the luck and started the haul for home.
我记得当初如何来到此地
And I 'members how it lead us here...
我们心存感激 因为我们看到从前的景象
...and how we was heartful because we seen what there once was.
只要看一眼 我们便了解一切
One look, and we knewed we'd got it straight.
那些在我们之前的人 所知道和所做的一切全超乎我们理解
Those what had gone before had knowing of things beyond our reckoning...
让我们连做梦也想不到
...even beyond our dreaming.
光阴不停地流逝
Time counts and keeps counting.
我们现在知道
And we knows now...
寻找失落的事物 过程并不容易
...finding the trick of what's been and lost ain't no easy ride.
但那是我们的路 我们的必经之路
But that's our track. We got to travel it.
没有人知道它将带领我们前往何方
And there ain't nobody knows where it's gonna lead.
然而 我们每天晚上仍叙说故事
Still and all, every night we does the Tell...
好让我们 记得自己的身份和来处
...so that we 'member who we was and where we came from.
但我们最记得的是那发现我们的人
But most of all we 'members the man who finded us...
带领救援行动的那个人
...him that came the salvage.
我们点亮城市 不仅是为了他
And we lights the city. Not just for him...
也是给所有仍在外面努力的人
...but for all of them that are still out there.
因为我们知道将来会有一晚…
Because we knows there'll come a night...
当他们看到远处的灯光…
...when they sees the distant light...
他们将能返回家园
...and they'll be coming home.
[献给拜伦]